# **Benjamin Perrault**

▶ benjaminperrault.com 🗷 benjamin.perrault@gmail.com 👂 Tulsa, Oklahoma 🔘 benjaminperrault

#### PROFILE

I'm a full-stack software engineer based in Tulsa, Oklahoma with multiple years of experience building with Ruby, JavaScript, & Go. Most recently I co-created Nexus, a tool for generating and deploying GraphQL APIs to AWS. Over the past 2.5 years, I've built a solid foundation in web engineering through a deliberate focus on mastery of software fundamentals. I'm a curious, tech-agnostic lifelong learner eager to explore new languages, frameworks, and tools.

## SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript (ES6+), Ruby, Golang, SQL, HTML/CSS

Frameworks, Libraries, Databases

Node.js, Express, React, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL

**Tools & Technologies** 

Git, GitHub, Docker, Bash, RESTful APIs, Terraform, DigitalOcean, AWS Cloud (Fargate, ECS, ECR), Heroku

### **{}** TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Nexus, Co-Creator & Software Engineer -- nexus-graphql.github.io ☑

2022 - present

An open-source tool that generates a GraphQL API from multiple data sources and deploys to AWS cloud infrastructure, abstracting away dozens of manual steps and reducing hours of developer time to a few commands.

- Led development of the core command line interface for API generation & deployment (Node.js, GraphQL Mesh, AWS)
- Built a responsive dashboard that facilitates API customization, testing, and monitoring (React, Express, TailwindCSS)
- Designed and implemented a re-deployment notification system, automated local test server hot-reloading, and built a dynamic guided GUI for users to configure linking data across sources (React, Express, Node.js)
- Resolved server over-fetching & N+1 issues with programmatic schema extensions and resolvers (GraphQL, YAML)
- Containerized server code for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure and collaborated to automate AWS deployment and teardown (Docker, AWS CLI, Terraform, ECR, ECS Fargate)
- Authored an in-depth technical case study: nexus-graphql.github.io

Software Engineer

A selection of the projects developed during my 2.5-year career transition:

- Request Cloud A database-backed webhook request inspection and debugging application (React, Express, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, deployed to Digital Ocean Droplet)
- Airline Routes An interactive SVG map for viewing and sorting airline routes (React, JavaScript, Node.js)
- Todo Tracker A Single Page Application backed by a PostgreSQL database (Ruby, Sinatra, ERB, SQL, PostgreSQL)

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Freelance,** Marketing Consultant

2018 – 2022

2020 - 2022

- Designed and managed marketing campaigns for a diverse set of clients including an iTunes top 100 entrepreneurship
  podcast, a non-profit foundation that has brought 2,000+ remote workers to Tulsa, and a world-class classical pianist
- Built the digital strategy and SEO campaign for a legal group that generates 900 organic leads per year

**918.Software,** Project Manager (contract)

2018

- Managed client-developer relationship of a remote engineering team across 3 countries using Zoom, Slack, and Trello
- Developed key feature requirements and app workflows from client mockups and user interviews
- Manually tested application workflows each sprint and wrote comprehensive bug reports

#### **Gitwit Creative,** Marketing Campaign Director

2015 - 2018

- Grew the marketing strategy team from 0 to 4 people and generated revenue of over \$500k (primarily recurring)
- Collaborated with founders to develop goals, processes, and internal documentation to grow the team of 12 to 25+

#### **EDUCATION**

**Launch School,** Software Engineering & Full-Stack Web Development ☑

2020 - 2022

A multi-year mastery-based curriculum of full-stack programming fundamentals from first principles.

**University of Tulsa,** B.S. Business Administration & B.A. Spanish Language

2011 - 2014